Guide to the Russell and Sigurd Varian Papers
Stanford University Libraries.
- Dorothy Varian Papers, 1930-1988; Series 4
  - Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-1993-078
    - Sheila-Wenonah: will correspondence (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Eric Varian family: Joan, Sheila, etc. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Property files for Sheila (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Estate - Education Fund Tabulation (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence: Dorothy Varian and others (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Varian Foundation: U. S. Coast and Geodetic Survey Agreement (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Letters acknowledged (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Inventory - financial data (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - J. S. Varian stock (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Trustees for Conservation (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - CA - Varian Foundation Grants (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Foundation Grant Requests (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Foundation Contributions (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Misc. - Varian Foundation Trust Fund (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Varian Foundation Misc., 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Varian [?] General Foundation data (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Varian Foundation: minutes and weekly summary, financial statements, Stanford pledge (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Varian estate (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Ana Nuevo Interpretive Associations (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Resumes (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Friday, July 18, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Environmental Impact in Alaska (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Alaska Material (Box 2, Folder NF)
    - Sheila Varian: notes and interest invoices (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "A Proposal for the Varian Foundation from the San Carlos Apache Indian Tribe" (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Varian Associates: Retiree Medical Plan (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Castle Rock Adv. Committee Mailing List (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Varianettes, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Varianettes (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Varianettes (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Financial Data (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Alaskan correspondence (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - AYH literature (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - AYH correspondence, minutes, Bd of Advisors (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Ansel Adams (two letters to Dorothy, clippings, postcards of his photographs) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Portfolio (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - AIA - Jury - Orchids and onions (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Alpine Chalet (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Alumnae resources (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Alumnae resources (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Big Sur Data and Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - California League of Conservation Voters (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Calif. State Park & Recreation Commission (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Citizens Advisory Committee (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - CLOG (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Council for a Livable World (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - City of Cupertino (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Bryan's Canyon, Cupertino (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Community Foundation of Santa Clara County (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Duveneck (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Filoli (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Lon Garrison (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Halcyon House (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Friends of Hidden Valley (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Hidden Valley Advisory Board (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Misc. Foundation Catalogues (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Robert Hill cards, publicity (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Irish finances (Box 3, Folder NF)
    - Irish trip (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Richard J. Jenkins (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Richard Leanord (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - League of Women Voters (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Misc. list of names (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Holly Middleton, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Mid-Peninsula Regional Park District (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - National Park Info. (in California) (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Nature Conservancy (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Peninsula Community Foundation (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Peninsula Conservation Center Groups (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Peninsula Open Space Trust (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - People for Open Space (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - San Francisco Opera (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Saratoga Horticultural Foundation (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Sierra Club (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Stanford Library use regulation (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Assoc. - Stanford Libraries (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Stanford Associates (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Urban Coalition (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - USGS Releases (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - USGS (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Varian Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Dorothy Varian and family publicity (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - DV personal (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Verardo, Jennie (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Dorothy Varian: publicity (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Christmas letters (Box 3, Folder NF)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder NF)
    - DV publicity and Ireland (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Varian: solar cells (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Varian vs. Varian (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Women of Achievement: League and Friends (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Women of Achievement (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Sempervirens Funds (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Mt. Echo (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - CA - projects (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Conservation Associates: Initial Organization, correspondence, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Conservation Associates: Arctic International Wildlife Range (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - CA: Whitehorse Conference - International Arctic Wildlife Range (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - CA: Misc. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - List of World Conf. Participants (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Pipeline (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Alaska (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - George Collins (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Doris Leanord (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - California History Center: correspondence, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - California History Center Foundation: Dorothy Varian (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - History Center: docents (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - History Center: Trianon; misc. correspondence; data on Center to 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - California History Center Foundation (notebook) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Trianon - History Center Foundation - By-laws (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Trianon - History Center Foundation - Bd. meetings (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - History Center Membership - fundraising (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Trianon - History Center Foundation - financial statements (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - History Center Development Plan (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - History Center (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - History Center (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - History Center: events, publicity (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - History Center (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - History Center (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Trianon Bd. Meeting (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Sempervirons Funds, April 1988 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- John O. Varian Papers, 1884-1934; Series 5
  Correspondence with Henry Cowell, Anne Hadden, and others; letters to his wife Agnes Dickson Varian; manuscripts and typescripts of his poetry, essays, and stories; and published works.
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Cowell, Henry (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Hadden, Anne, circa 1914-1916 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hadden, Anne, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Hadden, Anne, Christmas cards (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, 1907-1914 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, cards and fragments (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Varian, Agnes Dickson, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Varian, Agnes Dickson, circa 1898-1926 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Varian, Agnes Dickson, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Wilson, Maude J., 1911-1927 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Drafts of letters to Louise Awerdick and Henry Calley (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Drafts of letters re Charlotte Osborne estate, circa 1917 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous outgoing letters, cards, and fragments (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Calley, Sybil, 1914 and undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Cowell, Henry, 1923-1929 and undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Harrison, Ernest (Harry), undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Little, George Blakesley, 1914-1928 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Munger, Dell H. and Munger, Frieda, 1914-1923 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Varian family members, Ireland, 1894-1930 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Letters received, A - D (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Letters received, E - J (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Letters received, K - M (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Letters received, N - Z (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Letters received, no last name (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Personal Papers
    - Daniel, H. B., fragment of letter to "Louie" concerning death of John O. Varian, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Irish Press Corporation, stock certificate, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Patent for harp, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Temple of the People (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Writings
    - Poetry manuscripts (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
    - Poetry typescripts (Box 2, Folder 7-13)
    - "Bamba," typescript, 34 pages (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "Bamba," Carbon typescript, 37 pages (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "The Quest - Book 1," typescript (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - "Tirawa," typescript (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Christmas greeting cards (poems) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Printed poems (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Essays and stories, manuscript (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Essays and stories, typescript (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "The Golden Gateway," typescript essay (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Ossian the Hero," typescript story (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Writings on the Temple of the People (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Notes (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - List of short stories (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Notebook of journal entries and writings (in letterpress book of the Osborne family, 1852) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Notebook, poetry (Box 3, Folder 11-15)
    - Untitled typescript volume of poems (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "New Day," typescript volume of poems (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Doorways Inward and Other Poems, Halcyon Temple Press, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Tirawa, Troubadour Press, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Troubadour, Vol. 3, No. 8; John Varian Memorial Number, July 1931 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Writings by Others
    - Harrison, Ernest, "Call to the Colors" (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Ingersole, R. G., "Song of the Tapeworm" (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Lovett, Thad, "J. O. V." (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Mukerji, Dhan Gopal, "Songs of the Indian People" (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Agnes D. Varian Papers, 1865-1935; Series 6
  Letters to her sister Aileen Dickson Harrison, John O. Varian, and Anne Hadden; letters from Ansel Adams, Henry Cowell, many Dickson and Varian family members, and Maude Jay Wilson; diaries for 1888-1921; and miscellaneous items.
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Hadden, Anne, 1914-1933 and undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, 1905-1909 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, 1914-1916 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, 1931 Oct-Nov (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, 1931 Dec (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, 1932 Jan (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, 1932 Feb-Apr (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, 1932 Dec (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, written from Halcyon, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Harrison, Aileen Dickson, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Varian, Eric and "the boys,", 1912-1914 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Varian, John, 1888-1917 and undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Letter concerning John Varian's death, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous letters, 1888-1929 and undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Adams, Ansel, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Awerdick, Louise, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Awerdick, Louise, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bargar, Margaret E., 1917 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Calley, Sybil, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Calley family, 1914-1933 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Cowell, Henry, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Dickson, Mr. And Mrs. (parents of Agnes), 1914-1923 and undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Dickson family in Australia, 1908-1931 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Duggan family (re death of Nan Duggan), 1922 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Engle, A. J., 1914 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Evans, Murphy, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Forster, Sue, 1921-1934 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Hill, Meme, 1913-1931 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Hill, Robert, 1914-1931 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Kent, Dorothy Varian, 1928-1934 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Moss, Elizabeth, 1914-Sep 1916 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Moss, Elizabeth, Oct 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Munger, Dell H., 1914-1916 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Munger, Dell H., 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Munger, Dell H., 1923-1931 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Osborne, Charlotte, 1915-1916 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letters concerning Charlotte Osborne, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Letters concerning the estate of Charlotte Osborne, 1916-1917 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Roche, John T., 1925-1930 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Rosenthal, E. M., 1916-1918 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Varian, Ralph, 1929-1933 and undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Varian family in Ireland, 1908-1933 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Wilson, Maude Jay, 1914-1916 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Wilson, Maude Jay, 1922-1931 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Wilson, Maude Jay, 1933-35 and undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Letters received A - I (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Letters received J - L (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Letters received M - Q (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Letters received R - Z (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Letters received on wedding anniversary, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Condolence letters on death of John O. Varian, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Letters and cards on her birthday, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Letters from "Harry,", 1898-1903 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous letters (no last name), 1899-1933 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous letters (no last name), undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Diaries and Bound Volumes
    - Diary, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Diary, 1892-1893 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Diary, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Diary, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Diary, 1897-1898 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1898-1899 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1900-1928 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous diaries and notebooks (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Album, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Pamphlets and clippings from scrapbook (Box 3, Folder 6-8)
  - Personal Papers
    - Manuscript essay, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Pamphlets and clippings of articles written by Agnes Varian (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Poem about Agnes Varian, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - School essay, n.d., and certificate, 1874 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Aileen D. Harrison Papers, 1895-1959; Series 7
  Letters to Agnes Varian and other family members; letters from Henry Cowell, Maude Jay Wilson, and many family members; and sympathy cards received on the deaths of Agnes Varian and Ernest Harrison.
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Agnes Varian and family, 1914-1922 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Agnes Varian and family, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous letters, 1916 and undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Drafts of letters (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Awerdick, Louise, 1916, 1931, and undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Beaufait, Marion, 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Calley, Aimee, 1915-1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Calley, Aimee, 1933-1949 and undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Calley, Ernest, 1914-1947 and undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Calley, Henry, 1922-1935 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Calley Sybil, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Calley Sybil, 1915-1916 and undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Calley, Phyllis, 1915-1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Calley, Phyllis, 1938-1949 and undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Calley family (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Cowell, Henry, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Dickson, Mary Ann Osborne, 1908 and undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Evans, Murphy, 1935-1957 and undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Forster, Sue, 1921-1936 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Foster, Walter, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Hill, Meme, 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Kaylock, Laura, 1906-1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Kent, Dorothy, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Munger, Dell H., 1913-1935 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Osborne, Charlotte, 1914-1918 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Smead, Billy, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Stuart, Phyllis, 1925-1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Varian, John O. et. al. On her birthday, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Wilson, Maude Jan, 1931-1950 and undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - A - Z (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified, 1895-1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Letters received concerning the death of Agnes Varian, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
    - Letters and cards received concerning the death of Ernest Harrison, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
    - Sympathy cards received on the death of Ernest Harrison, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Personal Papers
    - Notes by Aileen Dickson Harrison on the death of Ernest Harrison (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Photocopies of scrapbook pages (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Additional Papers
    - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Eric Varian Papers, 1916-1942; Series 8
  Letters to family and friends with a few letters received.
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1926-July 1927 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1927 Aug-Dec (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1933-1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Outgoing correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Outgoing correspondence from trip to Australia, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Christmas card made by Eric, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters received, 1923-1927 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Family Papers, 1836-1961; Series 9
  - Cowell, Henry, letter from W. H. Thompson, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cowell, Henry, programs and brochures, 1922-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dickson, Anna, essay and leaflet, circa 1880 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dickson, Kate, letters received, 1913-1922 and undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Duggan, Nan, letter from Kay [?], 1922 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hadden, Anne, letters received, 1908, 1931, and undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Harrison, Ernest, letters received, 1932-1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Harrison, Ernest, obituaries (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hogg, Winifred [mother-in-law of Sigurd Varian], letters to John and Agnes Varian, 1929 and undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Osborne, Charlotte, letters received, 1871-1916 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Osborne, John W., stocks (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Osborne, John W., resolution signed by David Starr Jordan, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Osborne family letters, 1836-1909 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Shaull, Ethel, letter to Agnes and John Varian, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Varian, Jane [first wife of Russell Varian], outgoing correspondence, 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Varian, Suseen, "Deidre," TS story (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Varian, Wenonah [Mrs. Eric Varian], outgoing correspondence, 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Varian, Winnie [Mrs. Sigurd Varian], letters to Aileen and Ernest Harrison, 1941-1947 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Varian, Winnie, letters to her mother [Winifred Hogg], 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Varian, Winnie, letters to Agnes and John Varian, and Eric Varian, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Varian, Winnie, letters received on the death of Sigurd, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Varian, Winnie, misc. letters received and vaccination record (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Wilson, Maude Jay, letters received and memorabilia, 1914-1921 and undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous family letters, 1837-1952 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Unidentified letter, from among Agnes and Eric's letters from Australia, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - List of momentos from Agnes after her death (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Financial papers (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Clippings and genealogical notes (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Memorabilia and miscellaneous items (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence envelopes (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence envelopes (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Clippings (Winnie Varian) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Clippings (Varian Family in Ireland) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Photographs, 1869-1959; Series 10; 1.25 Linear feet
  - Agnes Varian, 1873-1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Varian, 1894-1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Family portrait (John, Agnes, Russell, Sigurd), 1901 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Russell and Sigurd, childhood photos, 1900-1917 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Family casual portraits, 1940-1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Russell Varian's Boy Scout troop (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Russell Varian, 1913-1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Russell Varian’s hike along coast trail with Bill Hyde, circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Russell Varian, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Russell Varian, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Russell Varian family in Alaska, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sigurd Varian, 1915-1936 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sigurd Varian, as pilot, 1922-1930 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sigurd Varian family images, 1932-1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Sigurd Varian, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sigurd Varian's house and lab in Halcyon, California, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Agnes and John Varian – prints from Ansel Adams images (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Russell and Sigurd – print from Ansel Adams image (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Varian family homes, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Temple of the People (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Aileen Harrison, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Dickson family members, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Osborne family members, 1969-1901 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Family and friends, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Family miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Klystron development and Stanford researchers (W. W. Hansen, Ed Ginzton, Marvin Chodorow), 1937-1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Klystron history - Boston Airport, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Klystron history - documents, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Klystron history - early models, 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Klystron history - early models photographed by Sigurd Varian (negatives) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Klystron history - early models photographed by Sigurd Varian (prints by Ed Ginzton) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Klystron history - 40 cm c.w. klystorn (negatives) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Klystron history - instruments and apparatus (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Klystron history - model C (glass slide) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Klystron history - radar apparatus, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Klystron history - staff of Sperry San Carlos, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Klystron history - Stanford lab, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Klystron history - unidentified group of men (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Klystron history - Woodyard's 40cm c. w. klystron used for blind landing, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Klystron history - Woodyard, Hansen and instruments (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Microwave lab staff [Varian Associates?], 1950 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Varian, San Carlos location, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Dedication of Varian plant in Palo Alto, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Varian Associates - Russell and Sigurd with employees (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Varian Associates, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Varian Associates, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Varian Associates, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Varian Associates, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Varian Associates, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Varian Associates, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Varian Associates, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Varian Associates - buildings (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Varian Associates - costume parties (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Varian Associates - instruments (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - From album "Our Children's Wedding" (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dorothy and Russell; Russell graduation, 1947-1950s; 1919 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Sigurd (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Russell Varian-Dorothy Hill, wedding, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)